SOMPEETI WALLIBHODOME

Bangkok, Thailand | Phone: (66) 89 009 8967 | E-mail: sompeetiw@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Consultant with a focus on business and economic social development for sustainability and inclusive growth with over 14 years of experience in consultancy, sales, marketing and business development. Experience in strategy formulation and public policy consulting, research and policy briefs, project management, M&E, government and community engagement as well as conducting training for SME on digital marketing. International experience across ASEAN and APEC regions, managing diverse stakeholders, including communities, government agencies, academia and multinational corporations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kenan Foundation Asia, Bangkok, Thailand (February 2016 - Present) Senior Consultant – Business & Economic Development

- Conducts research on government policies and corporate strategies as well as prepares conceptual frameworks, proposals and budgets, and project pitching.
- Designs/manages/implements economic and social development projects and works on components of projects to ensure delivery of results and overall project success. Monitors and evaluates project's key performance indicators/ metrics for management reports.
- Manages relationships with clients and stakeholders in order to foster strong relationships for continued future partnerships. Highlighted clients include MNCs and public agencies such as UN Women, USAID, Office of SMEs Promotion and Board of Investment.
- Advises management and project teams on strategies and practices, including program development, curriculum development, learning tool development, communication strategy and content creation.
- Acts as a trainer and speaker on topics of expertise, including digital marketing and MSMEs development – digital marketing trainer certified with Facebook Media Planning Professional, and certified trainers for Google's Saphan Digital program

Achievement:

- Awarded 'Project Manager of the Year 2021' for performing outstanding project management abilities
- Promoted to head of Research and M&E unit, and later SME Academy unit for strong leadership, strategic thinking and management skills

Sripatum University Khon Kaen Campus (27 April 2021) Guest Lecturer

Presented on Marketing in Hotel Industry to students of Tourism and Hospitality program

Rodenstock Asia Ltd., Bangkok, Thailand (December 2013 – February 2015) Marketing Communications Manager

- Aligned corporate marketing with communication strategies to plan and manage overall marketing communication activities in 14 emerging Asian markets (e.g. Singapore, Hong Kong Indonesia and Cambodia)
- Ensured consistent and efficient brand communication that is aligned with corporate identity.
- Developed and managed annual marketing budgets to ensure efficiency in marketing communication, including P&L and financial reports.

Novotel Bangkok on Siam Square, Bangkok, Thailand (April 2008 – November 2013) *Marketing Manager*

- Developed marketing strategies and plans to meet organizational objectives and implemented marketing campaigns, and collaborated with internal departments to create marketing strategies, campaigns and promotions
- Planned, managed and oversaw production of print and electronic marketing collaterals, including print and online advertising, EDM, website, social media, newsletters, posters, brochures, sales kits, TV, and radio commercial spots.
- Conducted marketing surveys on current and new product concepts, market conditions and competition.

Holiday Inn Resort Phi Phi Island, Krabi, Thailand (December 2006 – March 2008) **Senior Sales and Web Marketing Executive**

- Managed and developed hotel's website, online communication, email and Online Travel Agents (OTAs) communication
- Planed and created collaterals and advertisements for the hotel, including managing photography, visuals and graphic design
- Built relationships with travel agencies and other hotel chain members.

The Brooker Group Plc., Bangkok, Thailand (September 2003 – August 2004) **Project Assistant**

- Assisted the Business Consulting team in researching marketing information through interviews with targeted personnel in the companies or industries specified by customers and obtaining data from secondary sources
- Analyzed data obtained from interviews and wrote reports

BLI (Thailand) Co., Ltd., Bangkok, Thailand (April 2003 – September 2003) *Project Executive*

- Created marketing materials, including websites and brochures to promote several major international trade shows and sold booth spaces at these events to Thai exhibitors
- Conducted surveys on the Thai market for show organizers
- · Searched out business leads and established sales

EDUCATION

Aston University, Birmingham, UK - MSc. Marketing Management, 2005 **Chulalongkorn University**, Bangkok, Thailand - B.A. English (Minor in Italian and Psychology), 2003

CERTIFICATE

- "Saphan Digital Trainer," Google, November 2021
- "Transformative Scenario Planning: Creating Your Strategic Foresight Literacy for Future Challenges," Thammasat Design Center, June 2021
- "Design Thinking," SEAC, March 2021
- "Facebook Certified Media Planning Professional," Facebook, June 2020
- "Facebook Lead Trainer," Facebook, April 2020
- "Marketing Research: Tools & Analysis," Strategic Business Development Center, August 2019
- "Marketing Strategy," Chulalongkorn University, March 2018

SKILLS & INTEREST

Languages English (IELTS 7, TOEIC 990)

Computer/ Digital Tools

Document: Microsoft Office (Word, PowerPoint and Excel) and Google Docs

Collaboration: Microsoft Teams, Trello, Zoom

Design: Basic knowledge of HTML, Illustrator, Canva